<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://faculty.baruch.cuny.edu/geoportal/metadata/bcgis_dcxml.css"?>
<metadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://faculty.baruch.cuny.edu/geoportal/metadata/bcgis_dc_schema.xsd">
<title>Express Bus Routes, New York NY, May 2020</title>
<creator>Frank Donnelly</creator>
<creator>Anastasia Clark</creator>
<subject>structure</subject>
<subject>transportation</subject>
<description>This line layer represents MTA New York City express bus routes. Express buses are long-distance coaches that take passengers from areas of the outer boroughs to midtown and downtown Manhattan and back, with limited stops. For Manhattan-bound buses, riders can only board the bus at the outer borough stops (no one may disembark) and can only disembark at Manhattan stops (no one may board). The inverse is true for outer borough-bound buses. The mid-section of each route is express, and no stops are made. Each line represents an individual bus route over a roadway for a specific direction. The unique ID for the features is route_id, which is a combination of the bus route ID and its direction; routes with a 0 run either northbound or eastbound, while routes with a 1 run southbound or westbound. This layer was created by the GIS Lab at Baruch College CUNY as part of the NYC Mass Transit Spatial Layer series, to provide access to mass transit features for basic geographic analysis and map making. The data was generated from the MTA's static data developer feeds. It was transformed and generalized from a GTFS format into readily usable GIS features using a series of python scripts. Please note: data in this May 2020 edition represents reduced, essential service due to the COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
<publisher>Newman Library (Bernard M. Baruch College)</publisher>
<issued>2020-05</issued>
<type>Dataset</type>
<format>Shapefile</format>
<medium>Line</medium>
<identifier>express_bus_routes_nyc_may2020.shp</identifier>
<identifier>https://www.baruch.cuny.edu/confluence/display/geoportal/NYC+Mass+Transit+Spatial+Layers</identifier>
<source>Metropolitan Transportation Authority, Static Data Feeds</source>
<language>English</language>
<isPartOf>NYC Mass Transit Spatial Layers</isPartOf>
<coverage>New York City, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>Bronx County, New York, United States</coverage> 
<coverage>Kings County, New York, United States</coverage> 
<coverage>New York County, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>Queens County, New York, United States</coverage> 
<coverage>Richmond County, New York, United States</coverage> 
<coverage>Borough of Bronx, New York, United States</coverage> 
<coverage>Borough of Brooklyn, New York, United States</coverage> 
<coverage>Borough of Manhattan, New York, United States</coverage> 
<coverage>Borough of Queens, New York, United States</coverage> 
<coverage>Borough of Staten Island, New York, United States</coverage>
<spatial>name=New York City, New York, United States; northlimit=272752.873521; eastlimit=1067309.746197; southlimit=120053.504637; westlimit=913090.689878; units=ft; projection=NAD83 / New York Long Island (ftUS);</spatial>
<temporal>2020-05</temporal>
<rights>Public</rights>
<license>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike CC BY-NC-SA</license> <license>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license>
<provenance>Baruch CUNY</provenance>
<accrualperiodicity>Semiannual</accrualperiodicity>
</metadata>